NICOLE WALLACE

Pittsburg, CA 94565

Phone: (925) 698-9244 | Email: nicole.elisaw@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nicole-wallace-09/ | Github: https://github.com/nicolewallace-09/ |

Portfolio: https://nicolewallace09.github.io/react-portfolio/

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Full Stack Web Developer who specializes in the MERN Stack with a Bachelor's Degree and 2+ years professional experience in Business Administration combined with 3 different Liberal Arts Associate's Degrees. Naturally curious, an eager life-long learner and open to new challenges. Top 5 Gallup strengths are Strategic Thinker, Adaptive, Learner, Achiever, and Responsibility. Always looking to solve problems and never overlook the little details.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Node.js, MySQL (Sequelize), NoSQL(MongoBD) **Applications:** Bootstrap, Github, Heroku, React/Redux, Handlebars.js, Express.js, Inquirer.js, Jest, Recharts.js, GraphQL/Apollo

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Travel Planner

Created an application to help travelers maintain their trip plans by creating recommendations for flights and hotels based on their search criteria.

- Collaborated with a team of 3 in order to create this custom-coded, engaging, web application using HTML5 and CSS3
- Personally contributed to both the front-end and back-end of this project.
- Designed and developed the UI and web page with Materialized
- Displayed the hotel information from the fetch API to appear on our two pages and store the data in local storage using JavaScript
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/nicolewallace09/techly
- **GitHub Pages:** https://nicolewallace09.github.io/travel-planner/

Techly

Created an application to create a social network for new developers. This application allows users to create an account, login, and logout.

- Collaborated with a team of 3 in order to create a user friendly application using MVC paradigm
- Personally contributed to both the front-end and back-end of this project.
- Created API and page routes for models using CRUD and rendering pages with Handlebars.
- Major technologies used were Handlebars, Jest, Express, mySQL, and Passport
- **GitHub**: https://github.com/nicolewallace09/techly
- **Heroku**: https://techly.herokuapp.com/

Pandemopedia

Created an application to help users in the United States track Covid-19 data, comparing global, country, and state data.

- Collaborated with a team of 3 in order to create a React single page application.
- Personally contributed in API fetch data through Recharts (Pie graph and line charts) and React components
- Implemented an interactive app where users can search for their state with API data pulled from John Hopkins University.
- **GitHub:** https://github.com/nicolewallace09/pandemopedia
- **Heroku:** https://guarded-ocean-19687.herokuapp.com/

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Recording Analyst/Operations Coordinator Belcampo Meat Co.

Mar 2019 – Apr 2020 Oakland, CA

Focused on operations and digital marketing of the business. Oversaw e-commerce/third-party delivery services, website, and mail marketing. Managed IT services, POS systems for restaurants, and loyalty reward applications.

Key Accomplishments:

- Implemented the launch of our loyalty app and helped grow our members to 10k within a year of launch
- Created marketing emails/campaigns to promote and launch our third-party food delivery services to become 70% of restaurant sales within a year of launch
- Built website marketing materials with development team to drive up traffic by 100% from last year

Retail Sales Manager

Jan 2019 – Mar 2019

Ulta Beauty

Concord, CA

Promoted from Lancome Counter Manager and became the Retail Sales Manager. Managed the team of cashiers, maintained sales goals for mass cosmetics, and ran the cash wrap. Key Accomplishments:

- Sustained 70% of loyalty member sign up with 90% data retention
- Expanded sales in the mass department with the introduction of new brands by maintaining stock, visual merchandising, and cleanliness to surpass the 10k goal each week

Lancome Counter Manager Ulta Beauty

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

Concord, CA

Promoted from Beauty/Prestige Beauty Advisor into a management role for the Lancome brand. In this role I upheld clientele relationships, hosted events, and maintained sales goals.

Key Accomplishments:

- Managed over 300 SKUs by ordering testers, out of stock, and replenishment
- Awarded certificate for having 20% of overall business sales of Lancome's iconic Teint Idole foundation
- Recognized for making sales 110% to goal in May 2018, 134% to goal in June 2018, and 150% to goal in July 2018

EDUCATION

UC Berkeley Extension, Online

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, & ReactJS.

San Francisco State University, San Francisco, CA

Bachelor's of Science in Business Administration (Management)

Los Medanos College, Pittsburg, CA

Associate's of Science in Business Administration

Associate's of Science in Libral Arts (Arts and Humanities)

Associate's of Science in Libral Arts (Math and Science)

Associate's of Science in Libral Arts (Biological and Social Science)